workforcehosting.com 2015-12-13

# Privacy Policy | WorkForce Software

### Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personal information may be requested.

This privacy statement complies with the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Principles, which has been approved by the E.U. as an adequate way for WorkForce Software, LLC to demonstrate that it complies with the protections outlined in the E.U. Directive on Data Privacy. In processing personal information, WorkForce Software, LLC complies with the following Safe Harbor Principles, as more specifically described in this statement: Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer (to Third Parties), Security, Data Integrity, Access, Enforcement and Verification. More information about the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

WorkForce Software, LLC abides by the privacy laws in the countries in which we conduct business.

### The Information We Collect

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the WorkForce Software, LLC website.

On some pages you can register for access to specific materials or to participate in an event, or request that a WorkForce Software, LLC representative contact you. The types of personal information collected to manage these requests can include any combination of the following:

  * Your first and last name
  * Your job title, phone number, and email address
  * Your postal address for work
  * The name of your employer
  * The number of employees retained by your employer
  * The HR and payroll software products that you currently use
  * The business goals that have prompted you to contact us

Additionally, if you apply for an open position at WorkForce Software, LLC, the online recruiting system may collect details about you to aid in the hiring process. Information obtained through this system can include:

  * Your first, middle, and last name
  * Your email address, mailing address, and primary phone number
  * The name and postal address of your current employer
  * Names, contact information, and addresses for previous employers
  * Information about your level of work experience and level of education
  * The type of job you are looking for, desired salary, and data of availability
  * Whether you are available for relocation if hired
  * Whether you are legally allowed to work in a particular country without sponsorship
  * How you heard about the open position
  * Your prior history, if any, of applying and/or interviewing for WorkForce Software positions
  * Additional questions specific to the requisition

This site utilizes Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. WorkForce Software may use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interest) with Google Analytics. Users of this site may opt-out of the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting by use of the Google opt-out add-ons, located at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

### Our Use of Cookies

Cookies are collected on this site via the marketing automation system [Marketo](http://www.marketo.com/ "Marketo"). A cookie is a small data file that is stored on your device or computer when you visit a website. A “session cookie” expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A “persistent cookie” stores information on the device so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. When you visit our Site, we may use a session and a persistent cookie. These Marketo-placed cookies may contain information (such as a unique user ID) that is used to track your usage of our Site. WorkForce Software employs cookies using the Marketo system to enable our website to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages are visited and by how many people, and also in order for our server to recognize a return visitor as a distinct user. The cookies placed by the Marketo system are readable only by Marketo, and cookies cannot access, read or modify any other data on a computing device. Marketo uses Performance, Functionality and Analytics and Retargeting cookies.

A description of each of these cookies and how to opt out of these cookies is below.

  * Performance cookies
  * Functionality cookies
  * Analytics and Retargeting cookies

These cookies enable the collection of information about how visitors use our website, including the pages visited with the most frequency and any error messages received from such pages. Visitors cannot be individually identified by these cookies. The information these cookies collect is aggregated and anonymous, and will only be used to improve the performance and functions of the WorkForce Software website.

To learn how to opt out of performance cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies").  

Functionality cookies allow the WorkForce Software website to remember information you enter such as username and your preferred language. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of our website.

To learn how to opt out of functionality cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies"). Note that opting out may impact the functionality you receive when visiting the WorkForce Software website.  

WorkForce Software may use cookies to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our Site to personalize your visit.

WorkForce Software engages third parties, such as Google Analytics, to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from individuals who visit workforcesoftware.com. No personal information is provided to third parties, but this data may be re-associated with personal information after WorkForce Software receives it.

To learn more about these and other third party analytical tools, and how to opt out of analytics and retargeting cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies").  

### The Way We Use Information

When we collect information through registration forms we may use it for any number of the following reasons:

  * To determine the appropriate WorkForce Software, LLC representative for contacting you or fulfilling your request
  * To determine your eligibility for a requested event or digital file
  * To send you invitations or special offers that may be of interest based upon the information you supplied
  * To extend invitations from select partner organizations that may be of interest based upon the information you supplied
  * To contact you regarding your potential interest in workforce management products and services

We also may use non-identifying and aggregate website visitor information to improve the design of workforcesoftware.com.

WorkForce Software, LLC may use the information obtained through the recruiting system to help determine eligibility for a specific position, to notify you of future job openings and hiring events, and to communicate with you through the hiring process.

We never use or share the personal information provided to us through workforcesoftware.com in ways other than as described above without providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

### Opt-out Policy

WorkForce Software, LLC offers its communication recipients a means for controlling the information they receive. If, at any time, you change your mind about receiving information from us, please use the opt-out link located at the bottom of each communication or email your request to [opt-out@workforcesoftware.com](mailto:opt-out@workforcesoftware.com "opt-out@workforcesoftware.com"). You can expect that such a request will be completed within seven (7) days of WorkForce Software, LLC’s receipt of the same.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to allow only the appropriate use of your personal information, we employ physical, technical, and administrative controls and procedures to safeguard the information we collect.

To protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your personal information, WorkForce Software, LLC utilizes a variety of physical and logical access controls, firewalls, intrusion detection/prevention systems, network and database monitoring, anti-virus, and backup systems.

We limit access to your personal information and data to those persons who have a specific business purpose for maintaining and processing such information. WorkForce Software, LLC employees who have been granted access to your personal information are made aware of their responsibilities to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of that information and have been provided training and instruction on how to do so.

### Data Integrity

WorkForce Software, LLC will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information collected is maintained accurately, completely, and kept current for its intended use. WorkForce Software, LLC will only use personal information in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected.

### How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

You can access all your personal information that we collect online and maintain by emailing your request to [opt-out@workforcesoftware.com](mailto:opt-out@workforcesoftware.com "opt-out@workforcesoftware.com"). We use this procedure to better safeguard your information.

You can correct factual errors in your personal information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. You can expect to receive a response to any such update request within seven (7) days of WorkForce Software, LLC’s receipt of the same.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

### Enforcement and Verification

WorkForce Software, LLC holds its employees and agents accountable for maintaining the trust that our customers place in our company. WorkForce Software, LLC will conduct periodic assessments to validate its continued adherence to this privacy policy.

In the case that WorkForce Software, LLC obtains knowledge of use or disclosure of information not in accordance with the Web Privacy Policy, WorkForce Software, LLC will take the following reasonable steps to stop the use or disclosure:

  1. WorkForce Software will formally contact the relevant party and instruct them to stop using the data inappropriately and/or destroy the data. WorkForce Software will advise the relevant party on appropriate use and disclosure of information in accordance with the Web Privacy Policy.
  2. If the relevant party continues to use or disclose the information inappropriately, WorkForce Software will take legal actions to prevent the continued misuse of information. WorkForce Software will also remove the information from its database to prevent further misuse.”

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding these privacy policies, please contact us.

Privacy Compliance Officer  
WorkForce Software, LLC  
38705 7 Mile Rd., Ste 300  
Livonia, MI 48152  
Phone: 877.493.6723  
Email: [opt-out@workforcesoftware.com](mailto:opt-out@workforcesoftware.com "opt-out@workforcesoftware.com")

### US – EU Safe Harbor Framework Dispute Resolution

WorkForce Software, LLC will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding the use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this policy. WorkForce Software, LLC agrees to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities located in the European Union or their authorized representatives for disputes specific to human resource information received from the European Union. All other disputes that cannot be resolved between WorkForce Software, LLC and the complainant will be handled in accordance with applicable dispute resolution procedures through the American Arbitration Association, which are available for review at [www.adr.org](http://www.adr.org/ "American Arbitration Association"). We strongly encourage you to raise any complaints you may have with regard to this privacy policy and/or our implementation of this policy to us prior to proceeding to the arbitration procedure described in this paragraph.

### Copyright Policy

The information on this web site may not be duplicated in any way without the express written consent of WorkForce Software, LLC, except in printed or electronic form for the purposes of evaluation within your organization.

The information supplied is distributed on an “as is” basis, without any warranty. WorkForce Software, LLC shall not have any liability to any person or entity with respect to any loss or damage caused or alleged to be caused directly or indirectly by the information contained herein.

Trademark names appear throughout this material. Rather than list the names and entities that own those trademarks or insert a trademark symbol with each mention of the trademarked name, WorkForce Software, LLC states that it is using those names in editorial fashion only for the benefit of the trademark owner, with no intention of infringing on the trademark. No mention of a company or trademark is intended to convey endorsement or other affiliation with WorkForce Software, LLC.

Customers should seek independent legal counsel to determine what laws and regulations apply to them to ensure that they are in compliance. WorkForce Software, LLC does not provide legal services or advice.

### Effective Date

This Privacy Notice became effective January 1, 2012. It was last updated November 10, 2015.
